<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orange Haus</title>
    <description>Orange Haus</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 13:17:01 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 13:17:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>StreamLink</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;StreamLink is an App Inventor Extension created as a part of an NSF project titled GIRLS Immersed in Robotics Learning Simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linkclientimage.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Picture of Client Device&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will provide co-robotics workshops run by Holyoke Codes at Girls Inc. and Boys and Girls Club of Holyoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;StreamLink provides video and audio streaming, as well as other data types, between devices across networks. StreamLink provides blocks to easily create apps such as video calling, chat applications, home security systems, and remote control devices. Devices just need a shared LinkCode and an optional password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;StreamLink works directly with the camera input from a device and provides a video source for the App Inventor video player, allowing for easy integration with existing App Inventor components. StreamLink is not just limited to audio/video transmission, but supports other common App Inventor data types, including Logic, Text, and Math blocks. An additional method of sending any object is provided, but should be used with an understanding of what is being sent in a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;StreamLink provides code blocks that add the ability to create an encrypted connection between authenticated devices through a server. Built on socket.io and NodeJS, the server is open source and can be deployed and customized as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/holyokecodes/appinventor-sources&quot;&gt;Extension Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tgb20/StreamLink&quot;&gt;Server Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/streamlink/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/streamlink/</guid>
        
        
        <category>app</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Robotic Mini Golf</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With a small group of students I worked on building a robotic mini golf course for the Holyoke Public library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main hole I worked on was a large jaw that opened and closed by raising your hands into the air. This was accomplished with a Xbox Kinect sensor reading the arm position of all the players putting. When their hands went about their head it sent a message through the socket server to open up the jaws and let the players ball reach the hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jaws were designed in Fusion 360 and plasma cut to bend into the shape, with room for an axle to rotate to allow the jaw to open and close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second hole consisted of a ramp leading up to two spinning platforms you had to get your ball across by timing when they would line up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/minigolf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/minigolf/</guid>
        
        
        <category>making</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken Tooth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A native iPad client for Rooster Teeth video content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video and photo content this app provides belongs solely to Rooster Teeth and its affiliated members. The purpose of this app is to allow for the viewing of Rooster Teeth content on an iPad. This app does not aim to compete with any Rooster Teeth products and requires all users to be a FIRST member of Rooster Teeth. If there are any questions or concerns you can contact me at jacob@orange.haus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-first-only&quot;&gt;Why FIRST only?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicken Tooth is designed to improve the Rooster Teeth iPad experience and I do not wish to take revenue from Rooster Teeth. I cannot serve their ads, so I require every user of Chicken Tooth to have a paying FIRST membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-i-request-a-feature&quot;&gt;How do I request a feature?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can join our discord &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/WV69dGw&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This is where all news and updates are posted and requests/bugs are processed. If you submit them any other way I cannot guarantee support. DO NOT contact Rooster Teeth with bugs/requests, this app is maintained solely by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-been-a-while-since-i-last-got-an-update-for-the-app&quot;&gt;Its been a while since I last got an update for the app.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one developer of Chicken Tooth, and I am not looking to take on any new developers. I also work part time and am a full time college student. This puts strain on my schedule. My goal is to keep up to date with new features when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/WV69dGw&quot;&gt;DISCORD LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chickentooth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chickentooth/</guid>
        
        
        <category>app</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trend Master</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Comparing Apples and Oranges with Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon used to host nearly month hackathons for building Alexa skills when they were first launching the system and I always wanted to join one, but either forgot, ran out of time, or just couldn’t think of anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The January 2019 hackathon came around and I thought I should actually try and make something. This is when I made Trend Master, a skill that can compare two items with Google Trends and tells you who won. This is based off a game show on Youtube I watch with the same name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mainly entered because the participation award was a Echo Dot Gen 3 and a Firestick 4K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add the skill to Alexa &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Orange-Haus-Trend-Master/dp/B07NPHJVQ9/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trendmaster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trendmaster/</guid>
        
        
        <category>app</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MinelyMod</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Making the creation of Minecraft add-ons simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2016 Mojang announced that the bedrock edition of Minecraft would be supporting mods through an add-on system. These Add-Ons were created with JSON and could modify the way Minecraft worked. I was constantly asked to create a tutorial in Minecraft modding and this seemed like a great way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a website in which anyone could make Minecraft add-ons using a Blockly based programming enviroment. To send the mod to someones device we generated QR codes with a link to the mod, and when opened it would install it to your Minecraft game. This system worked great and we even taught a class on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Minecraft kept updating the add-ons, almost 1 update a week, and I just couldn’t keep up with the new features and mobs they were adding. They have since leveled out, and even introduced JavaScript based scripting for the mods, so it is a goal of mine to have MinelyMod running again, modeled after Scratch 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has since been shutdown, and just redirects back to this post, but one day it will return. &lt;a href=&quot;http://minelymod.com&quot;&gt;MinelyMod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/minelymod/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/minelymod/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to Swift</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple class I taught in how to make tic tac toe in Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tgb20/Swift&quot;&gt;Github Repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swift is my favorite language to program in and when I got the opportunity to make a class for Holyoke Codes I was quite excitied. This is an adapted tutorial I found online to make it more teachable. With the introduction of SwiftUI and the recent acquisition of several more Macs I plan to make a new guide using SwiftUI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/swift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/swift/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First HAB Launch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started working with goMake to build out a app to track HABs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OvuRP-kzWhk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first launch with goMake using a very simple test application I created to track their balloons. I would go onto develop a full app with a full chat and map tracking abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original description was &lt;em&gt;“A time-lapse of the 40 minute setup of goMake-1. This balloon was in the air for about 2hrs and 50minutes. Our GPS on the balloon, both primary and backup, failed, so we had to drive to the estimated drop point and look up. We saw it hit the ground and spent 3 hours walking in the woods searching for it. We called it when it was getting late. At around 12:30am the backup radio started working again and in the morning goMake drove out to go pick it up. it was a great first launch!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/habdemo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/habdemo/</guid>
        
        
        <category>making</category>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making a Minecraft Creeper in TinkerCAD</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A tutorial I made for making a crepper in TinkerCAD to be 3D printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BoxEsX4SreY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M9ClCYBTnIk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first class I taught at Holyoke Codes. I showed off a basic use of TinkerCAD to create 3D models. We have continued to use TinkerCAD for many more projects and its still an excellent tool. This tutorial was featured on the TinkerCAD twitter account when it was first published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original description was &lt;em&gt;“Whenever you see a yellow flash I used CTRL + D or CMD + D to make a copy of  an object. How to make a creeper in TinkerCAD. Designed for Holyoke Codes but available to anyone”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/creeper/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/creeper/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Battlebot Restoration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Attempting to restore a battle bot found at a vocational school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tfbKbnMpgsA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was helping clean out the storage of a vocational school and found this battlebot sitting in a crate. Once I knew I was able to take it, I put my tag on it to take it home, drove back to my house, got our pickup, and then drove back to grab it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was build in the late 90s/early 2000s so the hardware inside is not very usable, but the motors and metal frame are still there. The electronics use an old proprietary control system from FIRST FRC so it won’t be usable. I plan to rebuild it over the summer, but as of now I don’t have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its attacking power comes from this mace than swings with a large geared motor. The spike on the end were originally missing, but I found them a few days later in another box. Overall I hope it will be a cool restoration, and I might even be able to compete with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original description was &lt;em&gt;“I recently found an old battlebot and I am planning on restoring it to its original working functionality. I will be uploading build logs as I make progress in restoring Nemes/Nemesis.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/battlebot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/battlebot/</guid>
        
        
        <category>making</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RoosterMons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A fan Pokemon game using RoosterMons from the RT Extra Life stream poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/auT25K7To04&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this Pokemon clone I was attempting to recreate a simple Pokemon game in Unity3D containing RTs RoosterMons. I got simple battles and tall grass to work, but lost motiviation to continue working on it as I started to need more art, and I am not good at pixel art. It also was taking a lot of time for a game that might not even be played by many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original description was &lt;em&gt;“A pokemon clone I am creating to allow people to play as the Roosterteeth roostermons in an actual game. This is the first build and I hope to have it finished by the end of December.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/roostermons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/roostermons/</guid>
        
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
